# **MOHAMED BASSIOUNI**

250 Bellevue Way NE #333, Bellevue, WA 98004 | (253) 906-0261 | m.m.bassiouni@gmail.com

## **Professional Summary**

Quality-focused Operations Manager with 12 years of experience leading and coaching high-performing teams in retail pharmacy operations. Dedicated to exceeding objectives and ensuring exceptional customer experience through creating positive cultures, overseeing compliance, and providing valuable programs and offerings. Known as a flexible, adaptable professional with a positive attitude and the ability to quickly adjust to new situations.

#### **Skills**

- Operations Management
- Strategic Business Planning
- P&L Management
- Regulatory Compliance
- Project and Program Management
- Directing Workflow

- Talent Acquisition and Hiring
- Team Leadership
- Performance Management
- Coaching and Mentoring
- Building Positive Culture
- Customer Relationships

# **Work History**

### **Pharmacy Site Manager**

Genoa Pharmacy, a part of United Healthcare Group.

May 2019 – Aug 2020

Auburn, WA

Overseeing the operations of Genoa site 10150 located in Valley Cities behavioral health in Auburn, WA. Serving the clients of Valley cities in the Auburn Location, the Federal Way location through the CMC program, the recovery place Seattle location through the Pyxis machine as well as several other valley cities clinics in the area.

- Primary contact between the pharmacy and the clinic, maintain excellent relations with the medical director, case managers and other clinic staff, and provide drug consultation services when required.
- Supervise and coordinate the activities of the pharmacy technicians and other employees and assume responsibility for other duties related to personnel.
- Promote and increase sales.
- Ensure company metric goals are delivered
- Responsible for hiring, coaching, and terminating employees
- Manage accounts payable to minimize debt write offs.

Pharmacy Manager Jun 2018 – May 2019

Safeway, Inc Auburn, WA

Lead, coach, develop, and manage a team of one staff pharmacist, five pharmacy technicians, and several support staff. Ensure a positive culture by effectively directing workflow and quickly resolving any problems.

- Consistently achieve targets by ensuring high quality customer service and spearheading initiatives to increase sales.
- initiatives and programs, including immunizations, medication therapy management (MTM) programs, diabetes care specialists (DTS), clinical outreach, and patient communications.
- Implement clinical Oversee employee and facility licenses, pharmacy regulations, DEA requirements, and quality control efforts.
- Manage the pharmacy inventory and ensure compliance of every order.

Pharmacy Manager Apr 2015 – Jun 2016

Fred Meyer Pharmacy Kent, WA

Lead, coach, develop, and manage a team of Two staff pharmacists, seven pharmacy technicians, and several support staff. Ensure a positive culture by effectively directing workflow and quickly resolving any problems.

- Pharmacy filled 2400 scripts average weekly scripts.
- Implement clinical initiatives and programs, including immunizations, medication therapy management (MTM) programs, diabetes care specialists (DTS), clinical outreach, and patient communications.
- Oversee employee and facility licenses, pharmacy regulations, DEA requirements, and quality control efforts.
- Manage the pharmacy inventory and ensure compliance of every order.

**Co-Owner** Mar 2014 - Jun 2018

Alexandria Drugs, LLC

Seattle, WA

Co-founded the business and developed strategy for business growth, account management, and customer relations.

- Created sales presentations and promotional initiatives to increase brand awareness and revenue.
- Designed advertisements and marketing materials.
- Recruited, hired, trained, and managed a team of employees.
- Built and maintained positive relationships with customers.
- Implemented efficiency improvements and pricing optimization to reduce costs and increase margins.
- Developed and managed the company's budget.

#### **Pharmacy Manager**

Aug 2011 - Feb 2014

Rite Aid Corp

Oversaw the pharmacy program for some of the company's flagship pharmacies.

Seattle South District, WA

- Hired, trained, coached, scheduled, and managed the performance of several pharmacy teams.
- Increased sales and prescription count.
- Developed and hosted multiple annual healthcare education and immunization clinics.
- Worked directly with customers to provide comprehensive, patient-centered pharmaceutical care.

# **Education**

#### **Master of Business Administration**

Easterns Washington University (March 2020)

## **Bachelor of Science: Pharmacy**

Alexandria University (June 2003)

Alexandria, Egypt

## **Credentials**

- Licensed Pharmacist in Washington State
- Licensed Pharmacist in New Jersey State
- FPGEC
- APHA Immunization Certificate